Giuseppe 'Crowind' De Frenza Game Programmer

☑ crowind.gdev@gmail.com | 🛅 GiuseppeDeFrenza | 🗥 Genoa, Italy

Profile



Born in Pisa, 1994

After getting my computer science degree I decided to focus on videogame development. I joined the TheSign Comics and Arts Academy in 2018, from where I graduated in september 2021 with full marks.

During my education I have studied and applied multiple fields, like Artificial Intelligence, Procedural Animations, Procedural Generation, and Tool Programming. My favourites were Shaders and Code Architecture.

I always try to be versatile: I extend tools and libraries when needed and I do extensive researches prior to implementing new algorithms or structures. I also have basic skills in 2D art and game design.

Work Experience

Programmer, Tech Artist *Untold Games*

2022 - Current Genoa, full-time

- Shipped It Takes Two for Nintendo Switch (porting).
- Shipped Batman: Arkham Trilogy for Nintendo Switch (porting).
- Gained knowledge in render pipelines and render debugging on Nintendo Switch, PlayStation 5, and Windows.
- Worked on versions of Unreal Engine, from UE3 to UE5 as a generalist programmer and as a tech artist the latter focusing on performance improvements.
- Implemented and adapted AMD's FSR and FSR2 to multiple environments.
- Taught the Materials section of Epic Games' kickstart program to various teams, both in English and Italian.

Office assistant2019 - 2021Lucca Manga SchoolLucca, part-time

Video Editing, Social Media Management, Mail Management, Database Management.

Education

Università di Pisa
Bachelor degree in Computer Science, 99/110

The Sign Comics & Art Academy | Event Horizon

Game Programming, 30L/30

Pisa, Italy Sept 2013 - May 2019

Firenze

Sept 2018 - Sept 2021

Personal Projects

Skills

Human Languages: Italian, English (C1 Grade B)

Languages: C/C++, C#/F#, hlsl, HTML/CSS, Java, LaTeX

Frameworks: Unity, Unreal Engine

Developer Tools: JetBrains Rider, Visual Studio, Adobe Photoshop, Vegas Pro, FMOD Studio, Blender

Version Control: Git, P4V, TortoiseSVN, Plastic

Unity Assets: Rewired, Amplify Shader Editor, Behavior Designer, Odin, DOTween

Extracurriculars

Fighting Game Community

2015 - Current

ToSmash - Super Smash Bros. Toscana

- Contributed to the organization of more than 100 Super Smash Bros. for WiiU and Super Smash Bros. Ultimate offline tournaments
- Designed the whole entirety of graphic products (*Power Rankings, Streaming Layouts, Advertising, Logo*)

Rivals of Aether Italia

- Contributed to the organization of more than 50 Rivals of Aether online tournaments
- Designed numerous graphic products (Power Rankings, Advertising)

Super Smash Bros. Italia

• Designed Power Rankings for Winter 2017/2018, Spring 2018 and Fall 2018

Misc.

- · Italian and English tournament commentary
- · Community management

Hobbies

- I'm an avid player of tabletop games, especially strategic games like Brass, Concordia or Scythe.
- I've played guitar and other instruments for years, I also recorded a short album with a video-game soundtracks cover band!
- I enjoy casual hiking since I was a child. Looking for chestnuts, raspberries and blackberries also makes the hiking experience precious to me.
- I'm a huge birds lover, especially crows, ravens and parrots.